

Francesc Porta Solsona

Games Programmer

Barcelona, Spain

(+34) 660 57 52 39

M fportasolegmail.com



HELLO!

I'm a passionate Game Developer, proficient C++ and C# programmer, with great capacity for knowledge integration and creativity. Experienced working in multidisciplinar environments. Co-Founder and Programmer at TeamUglyGames which will soon be releasing Ugly, its first award-winning title.

Find this all my other projects in my portfolio: https://francps.github.io/

· SKILLS ·

- C++, C#, Python
- Gameplay Programming
- 3D Engine Arquitechture
- PBR rendering pipeline
- GLSL Shader languages
- API integration
- Good knowledge of Design Patterns
- Machine Learning & Al
- Agile Methodologies
- Teamwork & Communication
- Problem solving & Creativity

· PROJECTS ·

- Master's Engine Tesseract
- Master's Game ShutDown
- Pectoral Muscle Segmentation
- ZORK!
- Goya's Nightmare
- Space Shooter Mobile

·ACADEMIC PROJECTS·

- Garlic OS Architecture
- Flex-Bison Compiler
- Multithreaded Systems
- Server-Client Network

· LANGUAGES ·

Catalan: Native Spanish: Native

English: Professional working

proficiency French: B1.2



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY



TEAM UGLY GAMES LEAD PROGRAMMER

February 2022 to Present - Barcelona, Spain

https://store.steampowered.com/app/1983220/Ugly/

Soon releasing Ugly, a 2D puzzle-platformer game made in *Unity*. Soon to be released on Steam, Epic, NSwitch and XBox.

Fully supports 12 languages, controls remapping, 3 game slots with shared settings.

Features 70+ rooms with unique puzzles, 6 bosses and 2 endings.

- Co-Founder and Account Administrator.
- Programming Lead: Complete Gameplay, Tools and Backend. C#.
- Audio Coordinator.
- Multidisciplinar hand: Assistant to Game Design, Technical Art and Production (agile).

UP2SMART INNOVATIVE TECHNOLOGICAL SOLUTIONS DATA ENGINEER & AI DEVELOPER

September 2019 to August 2021 - Tarragona, Spain

- Machine Learning & Computer Vision: Creation of predictive model for Medical diagnosis. Early Acromegally detection using combination of Machine Learning systems. Python, Matlab.
- Data Engineering:. Tool to automatically generate data sets used in Mental Illness Center for treatments analysis and optimisation. Mysal,
- Project Management: System Design and Project Plan for a set of prediction techniques for an Automatic Treatment Plan Reccomendation System for Social Service Centers.



1-ONE SANTÉ ET SECURITÉ AU TRAVAIL **WEB DEVELOPER**

June 2015 to August 2015 - Bordeaux, France



EDUCATION



MASTER IN ADVANCED PROGRAMMING FOR AAA VIDEOGAMES

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC) - Barcelona Spain



Universitat Rovira i Virgili (URV) - Tarragona (Spain)

